On Wednesday, September 10th, Charlie
Kirk was murdered in broad daylight. He
was a prominent right-wing political
figure in the US and had just started a
new campus tour. His first stop was at
Utah Valley University in Orin. He left
behind a wife and two children.
Immediately after his assassination, the
hunt for his killer began. Now,
authorities have identified a suspect.
This is how he was caught.
If you read this, you are gay. L M A O
capital O wo what's this question mark?
>> For an initial mapping of the video,
check out Ho's video. Link is in the
description. Kirk got into politics
really young and started Turning Point
USA when he was just 18. The
organization is committed to promoting
right-wing views in schools and
universities. Kirk reached millions
through social media and his podcast. He
tooured colleges to debate students and
had become a close Trump ally. He is
said to have played an important role in
Trump's re-election. Phone footage from
the event shows the likely shooter on a
roof about 430 ft or 130 m away from
Kirk's tent. He seems to be in a prone
position. Kirk is engaging in a
discussion with a student.
>> How many mass shooters there have been
in America over the last 10 years?
>> Before the student can respond, the
shooter fires a single shot.
Kirk is hit in the neck and rushed to
Tempenogga's Regional Hospital
immediately after. In footage from the
event, a person dressed in black can be
seen sprinting off the same roof after a
shot was fired. According to
authorities, he ran back here and jumped
down here. Shortly after, the
authorities released photos of the
suspect and a video where he can be seen
climbing off the roof and running off
into the surrounding neighborhood. The
FBI offers a $100,000 reward for leads.
At this point, a manhunt of tremendous
scale is unfolding. Heavily armed
officers are at the scene. Authorities
confirm that they found a high-powered
bolt-action rifle in a wooded area.
Increasingly, the FBI is under pressure.
Two suspects are brought into custody,
but released shortly after. 24 hours
pass and no one has been caught.
Meanwhile, the suspect, Tyler Robinson,
seems to have told a family member that
he shot Kirk. The family member is
believed to be Robinson's father, a
veteran law enforcement officer.
Robinson grew up in Washington, Utah,
about 3 hours away from the university.
The father reportedly told a family
friend who in turn informed the
authorities. Robinson turned himself in
late Thursday evening in St. George,
about 250 mi or 400 km from Utah Valley
University. Robinson's roommate
reportedly showed Discord messages to
investigators. According to CNN, the
messages included Robinson stating a
need to retrieve a rifle from a drop
point, leaving the rifle in a bush,
visually watching the area where a rifle
was left, reference to having left the
rifle wrapped in a towel, reference to
engraving bullets and the rifle being
unique, mention of Robinson changing
outfits. Trump makes the capture public
on Fox and Friends.
>> Looking real good. They have the person
that they wanted.
>> Next, Utah's governor steps in front of
cameras. Friday morning.
>> Good morning, ladies and gentlemen. We
got him. Investigators interviewed a
family member of Robinson who stated
that Robinson had become more political
in recent years. The family member
referenced a recent incident in which
Robinson came to dinner prior to
September 10th. And in the conversation
with another family member, Robinson
mentioned Charlie Kirk was coming to
UVU. They talked about why they didn't
like him and the viewpoints that he had.
The family member also stated Kirk was
full of hate and spreading hate.
Robinson is said to have engraved
phrases such as hey fascist catch and
bellachchow on cartridges found with his
rifle. Bellachow is most likely a
reference to the Italian World War II
anti-fascist anthem.
>> On the hey fascist catch symbols are
engraved as such. Likely a reference to
a controller sequence that releases a
bomb in the game Hell Divers. In
addition,
>> inscriptions on a fired casing read,
"Notices bulges, capital O, what's
this?"
>> Notice Bulge, "Oo, what's this?" is a
trolling meme. On a fourth bullet,
according to Cox, it said,
>> "If you read this, you are gay. L M A
O."
>> Amid such a heated political atmosphere,
this press conference is bound to
reverberate across the US. In a
statement prior to the capture of
Robinson, President Trump had blamed the
rhetoric of the radical left for
violence such as this shooting.
>> For years, those on the radical left
have compared wonderful Americans like
Charlie to Nazis and the world's worst
mass murderers and criminals. This kind
of rhetoric is directly responsible for
the terrorism that we're seeing in our
country today, and it must stop right
now. Cox on the other hand said this.
>> We can return violence with vi violence.
We can return hate with hate. And that's
the problem with with political violence
is it metastasizes because we can always
point the finger at the other side and
at some point we have to find an offramp
or it's going to get much much worse.
The allegations against Robinson have
not yet been proven before a court.
Reporting like this is very resource
inensive. It's made possible by our
commercial partners. The reason we could
get this video out this fast is because
of our render farm, Super Luminal. It is
the most affordable, fast, and easy to
use Blender render farm on the planet.
Now you can use it, too. If you sign up
using the code Fern, you'll get $10 in
credits on a single purchase. If you use
our link, fern.deals/supluminal, Teals/s
superluminal.